A Guide to the René Jules Dubos papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA122
Rockefeller Archive Center
- (CORRESPONDENCE)
  - Mab-Man, 1967-1968 1981-1982 (Box 128, Folder 24)
  - Mankind 2000 Conference, 1981 (Box 128, Folder 25)
  - Map-Mar, 1972 1978 (Box 128, Folder 26)
  - Mas-May, 1963 (Box 128, Folder 27)
  - McGraw, Harold W., undated (Box 128, Folder 28)
  - Mor-Mou, 1970 (Box 128, Folder 29)
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1968-1977 1980-1981 (Box 128, Folder 30)
  - Ng-Ni, 1976 (Box 128, Folder 31)
  - Ok-Oz, 1982 1984 (Box 128, Folder 32)
  - Po, 1969 1982 (Box 128, Folder 33)
  - To and From Potet, Robert L., In French, 1930-1933 1947 1958 undated (Box 128, Folder 34)
  - Pr-Pu, 1979 (Box 128, Folder 35)
  - Ros, 1964 (Box 128, Folder 36)
  - Ru-Ry, 1982 (Box 128, Folder 37)
  - Sab-Sal, 1982 (Box 128, Folder 38)
  - San-Saw, 1970 1981 1985 (Box 128, Folder 39)
  - Schr-Schw, undated (Box 128, Folder 40)
  - Sea-Sei, 1970 (Box 128, Folder 41)
  - Sel-Sey, 1969? (Box 128, Folder 42)
  - Su-Sz, 1971 (Box 128, Folder 43)
  - Ta, 1980 (Box 128, Folder 44)
  - Th, 1964 (Box 128, Folder 45)
  - Vac-Vann, 1979 (Box 128, Folder 46)
  - VanV-Vau, 1970-1971 (Box 128, Folder 47)
  - Ward, Barbara aka Baroness Jackson of Lodsworth, 1972 1977 1980 (Box 128, Folder 48)
  - Woh-Wol, 1969 (Box 128, Folder 49)
  - Woo-Wy, 1984 (Box 128, Folder 50)
  - From Dorothy F. Johnson to McGraw Hill Book Co., [re having Dubos autograph Celebrations of Life], 1982 (Box 128, Folder 51)
  - Post February 1982 correspondence addressed to R. Dubos, 1982 February (Box 128, Folder 52)
  - To "Cher Madame", n.d. [From R. Dubos. In French], undated (Box 128, Folder 53)
- (SCRAPBOOKS)
  [See also Photographs].
  - Arches of Science Award, 1966 (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - Arches of Science Award, 1966 (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - Trip to Japan, [Loose items found in scrapbook binder], 1973 (Box 129, Folder 3)
- (Memorabilia, Programs, and Miscellaneous Items)
  - Société Scolaire de secours mutuels and De retraite de canton Demeru. [Copies of documents re school payment schedule for Dubos]. In French, 1912 (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - Passports, French, 1924-1935 (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - Marriage announcemnt, Marie-Loiuse Bonnet to René Jules Dubos, March 23, 1934 (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - "La Maison de la Mouche - École de Pêche" [announcement/card], 1935? (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - Poem: Love poem from René J. Dubos to Jean Porter, January 1, 1947 Postcard to Jean Porter, 1944, 1944 1947 undated (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - Poem, undated (Box 130)
  - Book Jacket: Bacterial and Mycotic Infections of Man, edited by R. Dubos, 1948 (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - Reconstruction de L'Abbaye de Fleury in Saint-Benoit-Sur-Loire [Dubos was a sponsor of this reconstruction effort], 1955 (Box 130, Folder 7)
  - New Year Card from Mshentsy?, 1960 (Box 130, Folder 8)
  - Guest admission ticket to the Rockefeller Institute Christmas Lectures, 1961 December 28-31 1961 January 2 (Box 130, Folder 8)
  - Poem (Box 130, Folder 8)
  - Invitation from - the Prince and Princess of Liege Poem, "The Perils of Purity", author unknown, 1961 (Box 130, Folder 9)
  - Soirée Musicale, program and thank you note, 1963 (Box 130, Folder 10)
  - Wesleyan University, map of campus, vitaes of various individuals, and faculty and staff directory, 1964-1965 (Box 130, Folder 11)
  - Postcards, panoramic views of Bellagio, 1969 (Box 130, Folder 12)
  - France-America Society Luncheon-Guest List, 1972 (Box 130, Folder 13)
  - Note with title of a book written on it (Box 130, Folder 13)
  - Exhibition - Monadnock Exhibition, Keene State College, Keene, New Hampshire, 1974 (Box 130, Folder 14)
  - Brochure - Arc Centre Internationale et de Reflections Senans sur le Futur [Center for the Future] In French and English Card, "Congratulations", signed by various individuals, 1975 (Box 130, Folder 15)
  - Invitation - Ambassador of the Netherlands dinner party, February 11, 1976 (Box 130, Folder 16)
  - Program: Recording for the Blind, "Macdonald Award to David Hartman, M.D. (Box 130, Folder 16)
  - Program - Conferring of Honorary Degrees on Alan Battersby, Michael Heidei Berger and Irvine Page, "The Rockefeller Institute Hospital, 1910-1955", 1977 (Box 130, Folder 17)
  - Pamphlet - "The Art of Living in the Cultural Revolution", Lecture Series [non-Dubos], San Francisco Museum of Art, March 5-May, 1978 (Box 130, Folder 18)
  - Agenda - Paris, France Trip, May 23 (Box 130, Folder 18)
  - Dinner Menu - The Royal Society of Arts and Sciences of Goteborg, September 10 (Box 130, Folder 18)
  - NY Times - Poem and Business card to Dr. J.D. Haan (Box 130, Folder 18)
  - Research topics for Dubos film (Box 130, Folder 18)
  - GEO promotional pamphlet [Dubos is listed as a member of the Board of Advisors] (Box 130, Folder 18)
  - Exhibition, "Ice Age Art", Calif. Academy of Sciences, February 17-August 31, 1979 (Box 130, Folder 19)
  - Booklet/Brochures - "Saint-Brice: Vu au Travers de son Conseil Municipal La Revolution", by Madeleine Hery, 1980 (Box 130, Folder 20)
  - Dedications to Dubos from Doe Lang and Anne Steven[?], [may be a page torn from a book], 1980 (Box 130, Folder 21)
  - Program, A. Einstein, 1879-1979: A Centennial Exhibit Birthday Card, signed "Betty" (Box 130, Folder 21)
  - The Master Plan for the United States Capitol, Environmental Impact Evaluation and General Overview, 1981 (Box 130, Folder 22)
    [See also oversized].
  - France-America Society Luncheon in honor of René Dubos [seating list], 1981 May 19 (Box 130, Folder 23)
  - Program, "The Royal Abbey of Saint Denis in the Time of Abbot Suger (1122-1151)", The Cloisters, March 31-May 31 (Box 130, Folder 23)
  - Program, President Anwar-el-Sadat Reception, August 7 (Box 130, Folder 23)
  - Invitation, Reception celebrating publication of Celebrations of Life, October 14 (Box 130, Folder 23)
  - Thank you note from Kuo-yi Wang, November 11 (Box 130, Folder 23)
  - Book Jacket, Celebrations of Life, circa 1981 (Box 130, Folder 23)
  - The American Academy of Arts and Sciences Bulletin, January 13, 1982 (Box 130, Folder 24)
  - Postcard requesting Dubos reprint (Box 130, Folder 24)
  - Invitation, Benefit Cocktail Reception for the Planetary Initiative Benefit Committee, February 8 (Box 130, Folder 24)
  - Invitation to attend the film, "Health at Work", June 9 [Dubos is in the film] (Box 130, Folder 24)
  - The Open University, Course on "Perspectives on Health and Disease", 1983 (Box 130, Folder 25)
    [Includes Dubos' " Mirage of Health"].
  - Exhibit/Mural, People's Environmental Program [Informational Literature], 1983? (Box 130, Folder 26)
  - Invitation to "Eco-Passion: A Photographic Exploitation", Cathedral of St. John the Divine, April 12 [Dubos is on the cover], 1984 (Box 130, Folder 27)
  - Invoice for Photography, Clergy-Pontoise, The Rockefeller University, 1985 (Box 130, Folder 28)
  - Environmental materials re land conservation and the Willamette River - pamphlet and essays, undated (Box 130, Folder 29)
  - Public relations Publication, Headquarters, The Presidio of San Francisco, undated (Box 130, Folder 30)
  - Leather photograph wallet, undated (Box 130, Folder 31)
  - Advertisement for subscription to Human Nature [Depicts magazine cover with mention of a Dubos article], undated (Box 130, Folder 32)
  - Easter Message, quote from Mirage of Health, signed by Mabel E. Gardner (Box 130, Folder 32)
  - Christmas Card from Miklos Emhect w/ written message (Box 130, Folder 32)
  - Foil "Birthday Card" signed by Margaret Shannon, Linda Wohl, Mal Stephens, Elsa Peacock, Carol A. Kenwell and others (Box 130, Folder 32)
  - 100 Francs [French currency] (Box 130, Folder 32)
  - Housatonic Valley Association Membership Brochure, undated (Box 130, Folder 33)
  - Letterhead, International Convocation for the World Environmental Regeneration [Organized by The René Dubos Center for Human Environments, Inc.] (Box 130, Folder 33)
  - Envelope, "A Celebration of Only One Earth", The René Dubos Center for Human Environments (Box 130, Folder 33)
  - Membership application and newsletter, André et Berthe Noufflard Association (Box 130, Folder 33)
  - Poem, "Greetings", author unknown (Box 130, Folder 33)
  - Order form, The Professor, The Institute and DNA (Box 130, Folder 33)
- (MEMORIAL MATERIALS AND JEAN DUBOS MATERIALS)
  - MEMORIAL MATERIALS
    - Letters of Condolence to Jean Dubos, A - L, 1982 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Letters of Condolence to Jean Dubos, M - R, 1982 (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Letters of Condolence to Jean Dubos, S - W, 1982 (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Memorial Service, Replies to Service Invitation, 1982 (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - The Church of the Epiphany Memorial Service, 1982 February 26 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - College of the Atlantic, Newsletter, May 1982 [On death and lifetime achievements and philosophy of René J. Dubos], 1982 May (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - Memorial Concert, The Cathedral of St. John the Divine, May 23, 1982, "The Berlioz Requim". Invitation and program, 1982 May 23 (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - The Rockefeller University Memorial Service, 1982 December 10 (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - Commemorative Service on the Anniversary of René Dubos' Birth and Death, Cathedral of St. John the Divine, "René Dubos and Human Environments", [program], 1983 February 20 (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Memorial Tribute to Barbara Ward and René Dubos, "International Convocation for World Environmental Regeneration", 1983 February 23 (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - "Environmental Regeneration II", Award Dinner, Commemorating Dubos' Birth and Death, 1985 February 20 (Box 131, Folder 11)
    - "Revised NAS Memoir" by James Hirsch and Carol Moberg, "René Jules Dubos, 1901-1982", 1987 (Box 131, Folder 12)
    - Announcement, The René Dubos Bioshelter, The Cathedral of St. John the Divine, undated (Box 131, Folder 13)
  - Jean Dubos Materials
    - Correspondence, Burns - Yamaguchi, 1982 1984-1985 (Box 131, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence from Francis Dubos, 1986 (Box 131, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence from G. Trouillet and René La Saout of the Hospitalier de Pontoise [René Dubos Foundation], 1983 1985-1986 (Box 131, Folder 16)
    - Reference Notes [re René Dubos materials in the collection], 1973 1975-1976 1978-1979 1981 undated (Box 131, Folder 17)
    - Reference Note Cards, 1981-1982 (Box 131, Folder 18)
    - Reference Notes, undated (Box 131, Folder 19)
- (OVERSIZED)
  - Artwork, 1940-1942? (Box 132, Folder 1)
    Sketch of Dubos by Marie-Louise Bonnet [?]. Ink and paper.
  - Artwork, 1973 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    Sketch of Dubos by Constance Burke Schurr.
  - Awards and Honors, 1972 (Box 132, Folder 3)
    Frances K. Hutchinson Medal [Paper certificate]. Garden Club of America, April.
  - Awards and Honors, [posthumous], 1985-1986 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    Poster - Inauguration de la foundation René Dubos, [establishment of the René Dubos Foundation] September 12, 1985.
  - Book Jacket, The Bacterial Cell, 1945 (Box 132, Folder 5)
  - Book Jacket, Louis Pasteur: Free Lance of Science, 1950 (Box 132, Folder 6)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1981 (Box 132, Folder 7)
    University of Brasilia, September 14-16.
  - 80th Birthday Celebration, 1981 (Box 132, Folder 8)
    Calligraphy envelope.
  - Memorabilia, Programs, and Miscellaneous Items, 1981 (Box 132, Folder 9)
    The Master Plan for the United States Capitol [bound].
  - Memorabilia, Programs, and Miscellaneous Items, 1954 (Box 132, Folder 9)
    Cardboard Box, "Tuberculine Pour Timbre, Institut Pasteur, 100 Pastilles" [box was later used to store slides].
- (ADDITIONS)
  - Mss, René J. Dubos Master of Science Thesis: "A Study of the Decomposition of Hydrogen Peroxide By Soil and Its Possible Use as an Index of Soil Fertility", Rutgers University (copy), 1926 April (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - Mss, René J. Dubos Ph. D Thesis: "Concerning the Nature of the Flora Active in the Decomposition of Cellulose in the Soil, With Special Regard to the Activity of Bacteria in this Process" Rutgers University (copy), 1927 April (Box 133, Folder 2)
  - Audio Tapes (cassettes)
    - Lecture, McLean Hospital 150th Anniversary, 1961 Boston, MA, audio tape (Box 133, Tape 33)
    - Lecture, "Science In Human Affairs", February 29, 1968 Oberlin College, Ohio, 1968 February 29; audio tape (Box 133, Tape 34)
    - Lecture, "Creative Adaptations to the Future", 1976 St. Peter's College, N.J., audio tape (Box 133, Tape 35)
    - Lecture, "Man Made Nature", April 5, 1973 Oberlin College, Ohio, 1973 April 5; audio tape (Box 133, Tape 36)